const nfpa211Chapter4QuizData = [
  {
    id: "4_1",
    question: "Vent connectors serving appliances vented by natural draft shall not be connected into any portion of mechanical draft systems operating under _________. (NFPA 211 4.1.5)",
    options: ["Positive Pressure", "Negative Pressure", "Neutral Pressure"],
    answer: "Positive Pressure"
  },
  {
    id: "4_2",
    question: "Chimneys shall terminate at least _________ above the roof line where it exits. (NFPA 211 Figure 4.2)",
    options: ["2 feet", "3 feet", "4 feet", "5 feet"],
    answer: "3 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "4_3",
    question: "Gas Vent or Type L Vent shall terminate at least _________ above the roof line where it exits. (NFPA 211 Figure 4.2)",
    options: ["2 feet", "3 feet", "4 feet", "5 feet"],
    answer: "2 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "4_4",
    question: "Chimneys or Vents shall be _________ taller than anything within 10 feet. (NFPA 211 Figure 4.2)",
    options: ["2 feet", "3 feet", "4 feet", "5 feet"],
    answer: "2 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "4_5",
    question: "Chimneys or Vents shall be 2 feet taller than anything within _________. (NFPA 211 Figure 4.2)",
    options: ["12 feet", "15 feet", "10 feet", "5 feet"],
    answer: "10 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "4_6",
    question: "Natural Draft chimneys and vents shall not terminate at an elevation less than _________ above the flue collar or the highest connected draft hood outlet. (NFPA 211 4.2.2)",
    options: ["12 feet", "15 feet", "10 feet", "5 feet"],
    answer: "5 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "4_7",
    question: "Natural Draft Chimneys and Vents shall terminate _________. (NFPA 211 4.2.2.1)",
    options: ["Vertically above the roof or parapet", "Horizontally at least 5 feet", "Horizontally above the roof or parapet", "Vertically below the roof or parapet"],
    answer: "Vertically above the roof or parapet"
  },
  {
    id: "4_8",
    question: "Interior residential chimneys shall be _________ where they extend through closets, storages areas, or habitable spaces where the surface could come into contact with persons or combustible materials. (NFPA 211 4.3.1)",
    options: ["Fully Enclosed", "Left Exposed", "Insulated", "Partially Enclosed"],
    answer: "Fully Enclosed"
  },
  {
    id: "4_9",
    question: "Venting systems are allowed to extend into or pass through a dedicated circulating air duct or plenum. (NFPA 211 4.4.1)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "4_10",
    question: "Venting systems are allowed to extend into or pass through a a space above a ceiling used as a return air plenum, as long as it is installed in one of the 3 ways listed in NFPA 211. (NFPA 211 4.4.2)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "4_11",
    question: "The remaining space surrounding a chimney liner, gas vent, special gas vent, or plastic piping installed with a chimney flue shall be allowed to be used to vent another appliance (NFPA 211 4.5.2)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "4_12",
    question: "The minimum distance from the underside of an unlisted rain cap to the top of the covered flues shall be the _________ dimension of the width or depth of the covered flue. (NFPA 211 4.6.2)",
    options: ["Lesser", "Greater"],
    answer: "Lesser"
  },
  {
    id: "4_13",
    question: "Where more than one flue is covered by a Rain Cap, the _________ shall be used. (NFPA 211 4.6.2)",
    options: ["Lesser dimension of the highest flue", "Lesser dimension of the shortest flue", "Greatest dimension of the highest flue", "Greatest dimension of the shortest flue"],
    answer: "Lesser dimension of the highest flue"
  },
  {
    id: "4_14",
    question: "According to the NFPA 211, the net free area of a Spark Arrester shall be not less than _________ times the net free area of the outlet of the chimney flue it serves. (NFPA 211 4.6.4.1)",
    options: ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    answer: "3"
  },
  {
    id: "4_15",
    question: "Spark Arresters should block the passage spheres having a diameter larger than _________. (NFPA 211 4.6.4.1 (3))",
    options: ["1/2 inch", "3/4 inch", "3/8 inch", "1/4 inch"],
    answer: "1/2 inch"
  },
  {
    id: "4_16",
    question: "Spark Arresters should allow the passage of spheres having a diameter of _________ or less. (NFPA 211 4.6.4.1 (3))",
    options: ["1/2 inch", "3/4 inch", "3/8 inch", "1/4 inch"],
    answer: "3/8 inch"
  },
];

if (!window.quizRegistry) window.quizRegistry = {};
window.quizRegistry['Chapter 4: General Requirements'] = nfpa211Chapter4QuizData;

